# CINDY MILLER

6178 Lawson Way, Riverside, CA 92506 Cell: 951-315-7474 - cyn.elena@me.com

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

To play an active Role in the operations of the Company and to assist the Company in meeting it's goals. Not only work at a company but grow within a company. Self Starter with 15+ years in fast-paced customer service and sales experience. Personable and professional under pressure.

## SKILLS

- Creative problem solver
- Exceptional communication skills
- MS Windows proficient
- Microsoft Office Proficiency
- MAC Proficent
- Quick learner
- Strong client relations
- Floor set design expertise
- Proficient in cash management
- Shipping and receiving professional
- International sales support
- Credit card processing
- Multi-line phone talent
- Types 40+ WPM
- Critical thinking
- Attention to detail
- Word processing
- Flexible
- Works well under pressure

- Quality assurance
- Professional phone etiquette
- Articulate and well-spoken
- Customer service-oriented
- Accurate and detailed
- Excellent planner and coordinator
- Certified in 10-key
- Social media knowledge
- Pleasant demeanor
- Customer service relations
- Natural leader
- Strong work ethic
- Computer proficient
- Organizational skills
- Excellent communication skills
- Well organized
- Quick learner
- Verbal communication skills
- Team leadership skills

## WORK HISTORY

02/1999 to Current **Owner/Designer** 

## **Self-Employed** – Riverside, CA

- 15+ years excellent customer service & sales experience.
- Own and run my own website designing flower hair accessories.
- I sell vintage clothing from the 40's 60's.
- Business has been very slow due to the economy.
- Currently I keep my business to keep me busy and as a hobby.
- I create a signature line of hair accessories that feature flowers, Swarovski crystals, glitter, sequins and other sparkly adornments that are uniquely combined on clips, barrettes & lapel pins.
- My accessories have been sold to many clients all around the world.
- I have a high rating on feedback from my clients.
- I have one of the largest selections of accessories that continues to grow.
- I have feature my hair accessories at different salons and boutiques.
- I am a vendor at a special event in Las Vegas, NV.
- on Easter Weekend at the "Viva Las Vegas Rockabilly Weekender".
- During any of my time in vending.
- I was a power seller.
- My sales during this time always exceeded my goals.
- My accessories have been featured on celebrities and models in different magazines from all over the world.
- Politely assisted customers in person, email and via telephone.
- Described product to customers and accurately explained details and care of

- merchandise.
- Communicated with vendors regarding back order availability, future inventory and special orders.
- Provided an elevated customer experience to generate a loyal clientèle.
- Handled daily heavy flow of paperwork and cooperated with the accounting departments on invoicing and shipping problems.
- Restocked inventory ever month and reviewed cash operation data to verify proper replenishment.
- Bagged, boxed or gift-wrapped sold merchandise per customer's request.
- Ensured superior customer experience by addressing customer concerns, demonstrating empathy and resolving problems on the spot.
- Provided ongoing guest service, including giving fashion advice.
- Folded and arranged garments in attractive displays.

## 05/2015 to Current Instructional Assistant

## Riverside Unified School District – Riverside, CA

- Tutor individual or small groups of severely, physically or visually handicapped students, reinforcing instruction as directed by the teacher; monitor and oversee student drills, practices and related activities.
- Confer with teachers concerning programs and materials to meet student needs; utilize appropriate methods of instruction to achieve goals and objectives set forth in the Individualized Education Program.
- Provide instruction and assistance to severely handicapped students in social, selfhelp, vocational and community skills; assist students in toilet training and personal hygiene such as washing faces and hands; change diapers as needed; assist with feeding students at lunch or snack times as needed.
- Assist students on and off the bus; push wheelchairs and lift students as needed.
- Provide support to the teacher by setting up work areas, displays and exhibits, operating audio- visual equipment, operating educational training equipment and distributing and collecting paper and supplies.
- Participate in meetings and in-service training programs as assigned.
- Assist in maintaining a clean and orderly classroom environment.

## 10/2014 to 02/2015 Branch Administrator

## Walter's Wholesale Electric - Riverside, CA

- Resolve all inquiries and maintain inventory of all office supplies and place required purchase orders.
- Oversee all job lot billing for customers and provide all warehouse shipments and process all customer credits to resolve all customer issues.
- Develop and maintain effective relationships with all clients and staff.
- Strong organizational skills.
- Self-motivated and detail oriented.
- Ability to prioritize workflow and perform as a team player.
- Ability to manage multiple tasks and meet deadlines on a daily basis.
- Process credit card payments & check payments.
- This was a temp job.

## 04/2011 to 06/2014 Retail Sales Representative

## Express – Riverside, CA

- Providing a positive customer experience by offering assistance when needed, ensure product is on the floor and sized appropriately, and ensure all customers have a quick and efficient cash wrap experience.
- This position performs additional tasks, including stocking, floor sets, cleaning and folding merchandise, to support strong store operational execution.

## 10/2008 to 06/2009 Noon Playground Supervisor

## Riverside Unified School District – Riverside, CA

• Oversee student activities; supervise playground activities.

- Assist students through the lunch card line.
- To administer first aid for minor injuries.
- Supervised students at lunch and playground.

## 04/1998 to 03/2000 Instructional Assistant

## **Riverside Unified School District** – Riverside, CA

- Tutor individual or small groups of severely, physically or visually handicapped students, reinforcing instruction as directed by the teacher; monitor and oversee student drills, practices and related activities.
- Confer with teachers concerning programs and materials to meet student needs; utilize appropriate methods of instruction to achieve goals and objectives set forth in the Individualized Education Program.
- Provide instruction and assistance to severely handicapped students in social, selfhelp, vocational and community skills; assist students in toilet training and personal hygiene such as washing faces and hands; change diapers as needed; assist with feeding students at lunch or snack times as needed.
- Assist students on and off the bus; push wheelchairs and lift students as needed.
- Provide support to the teacher by setting up work areas, displays and exhibits, operating audio- visual equipment, operating educational training equipment and distributing and collecting paper and supplies.
- Participate in meetings and in-service training programs as assigned.
- Assist in maintaining a clean and orderly classroom environment.

## 10/1992 to 12/1999 Credit Analyst

## **Credit Reports Inc** – Riverside, CA

- Responsible for distributing work to a team of eight.
- Analyzed credit reports for a mortgage loan.
- Entered information to the computer i.e., employment, credit, income, and property addresses.
- QC'd credit report before we send it to our mortgage clients and borrower.
- Trained new employees on all out of state files i.e., analyzing and calling.
- Responsible for pulling credit from TRW, Trans Union and Equifax.
- Also pulled statewide on all tax liens and judgments.
- Responsible for keeping confidential information such as credit card numbers, checking and savings account numbers, social security numbers and employment history.
- Answered an average of 100+ calls per day by addressing customer inquiries, solving problems and providing new product information.

**EDUCATION** 

1992

**High School Diploma**:

Ramona High School - Riverside, CA